A Guide to the Papers of Thomas Perkins Abernethy, 1943-1975
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Thomas Perkins Abernethy 1943-1975
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12765-e
This collection consists of ca. 400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The material was presented to Alderman Library January 14, 1976 by the estate of Thomas Perkins Abernethy through Mrs. Charles M. Davison, Jr.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Thomas Perkins Abernethy Collection contains approximately 400 items which range in date from 1943 to 1975. This collection is made up primarily of personal material of T. P. Abernethy and contains no professional papers or correspondence. The bulk of the collection is comprised of personal letters from his immediate family - his brothers, aunts, cousins, and in-laws - as well as friends. The collection also contains the letters written to Mrs. Charles M. Davison, Jr. concerning Thomas Perkins Abernethy from Abernethy's family. Various newspaper clippings, photographs and memorablia, such as greeting cards and poems which were kept by Abernethy, comprise the remainder of this collection.
Arrangement
Like the preceding portions of the Abernethy Collection, this addition's correspondence was organized in chronological order with the miscellaneous newspaper clippings, photographs and mementos placed at the end.
Contents List
- Correspondence of T. Perkins Abernethy: John Abernethy, Aunt Mary, H. H. Bellot 1943-1948
- Correspondence of T. Perkins Abernethy: Family Correspondence and Friends 1950-1959
- Correspondence of Thomas Perkins Abernethy: Wife, Relatives, Friends and Library Donations to Marion Institute 1960-1969
- Correspondence of Thomas Perkins Abernethy: Relatives and Friends 1970-1975
- Correspondence of Thomas Perkins Abernethy: Letters to Mrs. Charles M. Davison, Jr. from TPA's Relatives concerning TPA 1972-1975
- Correspondence of Thomas Perkins Abernethy: Relatives and Friends n. d.
- Articles about Thomas Perkins Abernethy 1960, 1961, 1964, 1970, 1972 & n. d.
- Articles about Relatives kept by Thomas Perkins Abernethy 1954, 1956, 1957, 1959 & n. d.
- Photographs of Thomas Perkins Abernethy and Relatives n. d.
- Greeting and Announcement Cards of Thomas Perkins Abernethy n. d.
- Thomas Perkins Abernethy: Medical Bills to TPA for wife Ida's illness 1968
- Miscellaneous: Marriage Certificate, Discarded Manuscript, Article about Colleague, Dustcover Congressional Record Speech by Relative, Short Story by Brother New York Times list of White House Library, The Antecedents of the Abernethy Family1917; 1963-1972 & n. d.